Singularity is here. Yes. Oh my god. How
lucky are we to be alive now during the
singularity? I mean I I know you guys
know this. I mean we feel the speed up,
right? Every day I wake up and check my
ex channels which I've curated. I I
check the conversations uh we have in
our WhatsApp group and the moonshot
mates like what just happened? What just
happened?
It's mindblowing.
It's absolutely mind-blowing.
So, uh, we have two incredible leaders
on stage and I'm going to kick off the
first question to you, Kathy. And thank
you, uh, Kathy, for your support of this
event and of the Future Vision X-P
Prize. So, so proud of what you and Lisa
Dodd have done to support this.
>> Yes. And thank you. Lisa is here. So,
thank you, Lisa, for all you've done for
this great event. So uh your team uh has
said the Tesla and SpaceX merger uh
could be announced this year. I agree.
Uh you know rockets satellites, AI, EVs,
robo taxis, humanoid robots, energy all
under one roof. And so the question is
what is Elon in your opinion actually
trying to achieve long term through this
merger? Do you think he's going to hit
any particular roadblocks? And I'm
curious, you know, does SpaceX AI or
SpaceX need to reach a certain valuation
before he pulls the trigger on that so
the dilution isn't too much?
>> Yes. Uh so we do think it's going to
happen. What is his ultimate goal? Well,
he tells us all the time it's Mars.
She's just uh creating a number of stops
along the way um in the form of a a
global you know connectivity broadband
connectivity business.
>> Yeah. The Dyson swarm.
>> Yes. Really unbelievable how profitable
and and h how big it is already from a
revenue generation point of view. Uh and
this Neocloud business that he you know
basically was a giant pivot in terms of
XAI. So, Neoclouds. Um, but Elon
believes that uh that the leader, the AI
leader in terms of frontier models is
going to be the company with the most
computing capacity and at at the
cheapest cost. And with orbital data
centers, he thinks uh he will be that
company. So he's really going to go
after, you know, the the open AIs and
and anthropics of the world. Very
determined.
>> SpaceX is my largest holding. Um, is
that your largest holding? What what's
the top of your stack?
>> Yeah, Tesla and SpaceX. And we do
believe they will be combined. So
interesting.
>> Do you think uh you know, so he has a
Chinese business
with Tesla, right? and he's in the
defense department. How does he handle
that?
>> Yeah, as one of the roadblocks out
there.
>> You know, it's very interesting to see
him sitting at the table with President
Trump and and Xiinping. Uh so, and we
know that May Musk is adored in China.
So, he's working all angles here. Uh and
there's even uh there has even been uh
talk that he's going to be able to um
develop a robo taxi system in in China.
So it's very interesting. Uh many people
would say that's the biggest stumbling
block given our defense posture and uh
and given uh how this administration has
you know basically portrayed the Chinese
as our as our biggest potential en
enemy. uh keep your enemies close is
what I think this this week is all
about. Uh so you know I can see honestly
I have now I am an optimistic person but
we believe that the productivity gains
coming out of this AI and just
generalized technology revolution are
going to be so enormous that we could
have a winwinwin here with China uh U
and and the US uh the U China needs to
develop a consumer economy and it can
turn this productivity gain into
increased compensation to really develop
the consumer. We need to uh we need to
be maybe more aggressive in competing
against China. We can use some of it to
cut prices. Uh so I think and that would
lower inflation uh and take away a lot
of the the fears out there from a policy
point of view. So I think that's what uh
Trump and Musk together are working on.
The Fed announced something like a 4.7%
GDP growth in the last quarter, which
was like double the quarter before. When
I interviewed Elon uh with Dave Blondon
last December, it aired the beginning of
January. Uh he said, you know, he could
imagine tripledigit growth within this
decade of the GDP, which is
>> is that cumulative or
>> per year?
>> Yes. I um I think I I tuned into that
part of it and it was like well so our
number is 7 to 8% we're accelerating in
the next five years to 7 to 8% real GDP
growth. I have heard him say
20 30%. I had not heard him say triple
digits and I wasn't sure if it was
cumulative that he was talking about.
I'll ask him. Uh, are you going to the
uh Roadster rollout on October 1st?
>> Um, we have we have been invited.
>> Okay. Yeah. Uh, so I was texting with
Elon and I think we're going to do a
Moonshots podcast with him from there.
So I'm excited about that.
>> Very cool.
>> Yeah.
>> Iman.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I think that one of the
interesting things that I've seen
recently like your view, Nick Hill, and
it kind of extends is Elon said that
Grockbot has hundreds of thousands of
installs now.
>> And obviously, it's a brand new line.
We've seen Muse with 3 million
>> 3.8
>> 3.8 million downloads. And then we saw
>> I'm sorry, 2.8 million downloads, 3.8
3.8 billion users, right?
>> Well, that's the Yeah, it's going to
it's obviously going to grow this entire
sector. And then Amazon Van Muse. So I
think one of the really interesting
things for me and you know I think Nicol
you been thinking about this a lot is
how do you tell who's who on the
internet when we have these AIs
intermediating us and
>> millions of them
>> then at what point are there going to be
more AIs than humans doing these jobs on
the internet itself because I think this
is one of the things that really drives
the massive real GDP growth right
because you have so much money being
unlocked through intents and being able
to represent what you want so I'd love
your insight on that
>> I think on The second part, um, I think
there will be more AIs than humans next
year. There's no reason for that not to
be true. There's five, like anywhere
between five to six and a half billion
people on the internet at any given
time. Um, it's not very hard to imagine
that every one of us has thousands of
agents working for us. They're coming in
and out, but like they're all going to
be there. And with consumer platforms
like Muse and Instinct getting out and
them reaching mass scale um I mean I
think they're primarily compute limited
at this point. They're not limited by
people's desire to have those things. So
I wouldn't be surprised like much much
like we had like one PC a PC on every
desktop a phone in every pocket like an
agent for every person and if you move
towards that v that vision then like
every agent has sub agents and like
those agents come about like to do tasks
and then they go away because you have
this main orchestrating agent that like
remains with you that has context and
memory. And so all of these agents are
going to be on the internet. They're
going to be doing they're going to be
doing things. They're going to be doing
things really fast. hopefully they're
aligned with us. We can have a
discussion about that as well. Uh and
and not with each other. Um and and and
so like yeah and so then the question is
like what happens then? Like what
happens in like 28 like well in at least
in our estimation as we look forward
towards the uh later years in the decade
these agents become full economic actors
much like websites became started off as
curiosities. I don't know if anybody
remembers geio cities back in 96. I do.
>> Yeah. So I lived through all of that
like you know I lived through uh if
people remember uh Blogger and Orcut and
these are old uh social networks um and
then and then we got websites we got
real websites that did real things like
we had the New York Times or the Journal
for News and then we had Amazon for
shopping and then everything became a
website. So I think everything
eventually will become like this
economic endpoint and at that point yes
these economic endpoints will not just
talk to us they will talk to each other
they will talk to each other on behalf
of us sometimes they'll talk to each
other because they're just trying to
accomplish a task and that is the most
efficient thing to do and when they do
that I think you will need like a way to
say like all right who are you like when
were you born what have you done
>> who owns you who owns you
>> who's responsible if you
>> who's responsible who owns the liability
like what is the provenence of your
identity, what is the provenence of your
compute allocation? Uh, and what are
your incentives? And prove to me that
you have done the things that you claim
you you do. Uh, or like you know, let's
say like this is another use case we're
playing around with on ARC, which is a
new blockchain we have. Uh, nothing in
common. [laughter]
Uh, and and and so there we're giving
agents money. We're giving them when
agents spin up like uh they need money
to act. So they need money for compute.
They need money to like a lot of these
are trading agents right now on
blockchains. And so we're giving we have
a credit program. So we give them we
give them 25 cents. If they come and pay
us back then we give them more money.
And so like so then you need a log of
like where does this happen? Blockchains
are great for creating like persistent
logs over uh many years. Uh because you
have distributed validator sets. You
cannot lie. One of the things that
happened in the hugging face hack was
like the logs got rewritten because they
were their agent's own logs. So what
happens if the logs are public? What if
the data is all public all indexable?
You can run your own verification on who
the agent is, what they have done, what
is their provenence, like what are their
incentives. I think we just move into a
very different world uh than what we are
today where it feels like a bunch of
teenagers like going about the world and
like we're waiting for the grown-up
agents to come about like
>> you know paint a picture for us when
there are millions or billions of agents
transacting
>> right
>> uh how superheated does the economy get
in five or 10 years? So it's it's really
interesting to think about because every
inefficiency in the economy uh needs to
go away, right?
>> Well, it will go away.
>> It will go away. And the reason it'll go
away is because if you don't take it
away, there will be some other agent
who's willing to take it away at cost
plus, right? Like essentially the
economy all efficient inefficiencies get
taken out by these cost plus uh agents.
So at that point we have uh a very
efficient uh capital allocation system
and and we have to believe that on the
other side of this very efficient
capital allocation system is this this
wellspring of ideas that is waiting to
get funded. Uh and so I do think like
the solopreneur uh like you were talking
about earlier today will will that'll be
a big uh big population. I do think like
uh uh capital formation will be almost
instantaneous. So if these things happen
>> my idea oh it's funded. [laughter] So
>> there you go.
>> Um so we're building primitives so that
can happen. That's what inspires us
because we want people everywhere in the
world to be able to form capital and you
form capital today by going to a bank or
like you know writing a note uh or
raising money. But what crypto has
proven really well is that you can use
cryptographic tools, you can use tokens
to coordinate and form capital. Now they
were less serious ideas in the past and
now they're going to be more and more
serious ideas in the future. So that's
what's exciting about
>> So let me let me follow a second. So uh
ultimately the question is why USDC?
Hawaii uh not Satoshi's uh you know
there have been uh native agent token uh
you know
created.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. Talk to me about how you think
USDC is like the the the best mechanism
for transaction for agents.
>> Yeah. Look USDC has already settled over
100 trillion uh in the last good
>> pretty good like yeah so over 100
trillion over 30 public blockchains. A
public blockchain has every transaction
publicly available. So uh it's hardened
infrastructure. Uh we have uh created
and redeemed close to a billion dollars
of USDC uh trillion dollars of USDC
today. Uh so when it comes to financial
infrastructure, you need it to be 24/7.
You need it to be 365. You need it to be
uh you need it to be cheap. Uh you want
to pay cents, not bips. Bips are
basically percentage points on the
transaction. So all of that
infrastructure uh exists right now and
what is going to be a great tailwind in
the new year is that the Genius um act
goes into effect uh come January. So for
those who don't know the Genius Act is
the stable it legalized stable coins or
created a framework for stable coins in
the United States and was passed last
summer. It takes 18 months to get the
implementation going and come January
it's going to be implemented. So stable
coin money uh can and can be held by a
business and count as cash or cash
equivalents uh in the United States and
you can transact in stable coin money.
So uh stable coins are good for this new
world because stable coins settle
instantaneously when you strike when you
swipe your credit card at the merchant
outside it takes them like three or five
days to get that money. So they're
essentially holding that risk that the
that your credit card uh your bank
account is going to uh move the money to
them at some point. So that creates risk
in the system. All of that goes away
with
>> it's like the Pony Express being
disrupted by by telegraph.
>> Yeah.
>> May I ask a question? Um
>> Matthew Prince at um Cloudflare Yeah. is
uh very focused on agentic commerce,
agentic payments. Yeah. And he believes
that we are going to need uh uh
blockchain speeds of 20 to 100
transactions per second in this new
world
>> and yet we are so far from that. Um it
visas at 20,000 per second I think and
Ethereum
not even that right Salana a little bit
more so how do we get from here to there
what has to happen
>> we are approaching those uh we are
approaching it's did you say 20 or 100
or
>> 20 to 100
>> thousand
>> no
>> oh then then we are there um No, no, no.
I think 20 to 100.
I think it's trillion. It's either
billion or trillion.
>> It'll be million. Billion.
>> It'll be It'll be million. Trump.
>> Oh, no. No. It would be million. That's
right. Because NASDAQ is NASDAQ at its
peak is 2 million. He's saying 20 to 100
million.
>> That'd be great. [laughter]
>> No, I know. But that but
it's it's the world that would be
>> it's the world we are moving towards.
Like
>> moving towards that. So how do we get
there? we are already orders of
magnitude like so our chain again arc is
orders of magnitude higher than like
what ethereum is able to achieve today
right so it's in tens of thousands of
transactions per second um it's an open
question about like you know how do you
get to 2 million to 5 million or 10
million TPS those are hard technical
questions still
>> uh we the one of the things that is true
is like as the demand comes the
solutions will follow right like in the
sense that uh Ethereum created an
architecture for uh what they call layer
2s and like they scaled through that. uh
I don't know what the right architecture
is yet for that scale like my dream is
that we will get to 100,000 TPS without
like you know without batting an eyelid
and from there we will get to a million
TPS but it's yeah if you believe there
will be billions of agent agentic actors
working on behalf of us all
participating
uh and transacting because agents acting
without actually transacting is not
really economic activity that's just
noise right that's spam
>> and so you need economic activity. So
yes, I I think we'll if that is the
case, I should call up Matthew Prince
and find out.
>> I mean, the problem at 20 million is
that you run into a speed of light
issue.
>> Yeah. I I haven't reasoned about it that
far yet.
>> Yeah. So, but then you can like have
different areas you can have insurance
on settlements and others. Again, the
economy finds a way like life finds a
way.
>> Yes.
>> I'm really looking forward to that. If
that is if that is the constraint like
you must solve TPS because we have so
many agents or like the economy is being
held back because we cannot deliver TPS
we will deliver TPS. There's no doubt in
my mind.
>> And Peter one other just to segue from
your last question. Um uh the you know
proof of humanity pro proof of humanood
is is really important. Um, do you think
I'd love to I know you're interviewing,
but I I'd just love to
>> I I pass the mantle to you, Kathy.
>> I'd love to know if you see orbs as a
possibility. Um, we have been working
with ATco and OpenAI and actually Mr.
Beast to try and figure this.
>> What a fascinating combination.
>> Yes. No, proof of humanity largest
largest number of followers. Yeah. All
all of them have huge platforms. I think
Mr. Beast is uh like I worked at YouTube
eight years and like
>> I'm only shooting for 10 million, you
know, viewers on Moonshots. He's got
billion.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I do think it'll matter. I think uh
uh human experience will get valued
significantly higher than machine
experience. I think we all have
intuition about that. Uh but we don't
know yet because we haven't seen it in
action. Uh I definitely don't uh I have
made active choices in my kids'
education where I I'm choosing for them
to be educated by a human versus being
like in front of a computer for like
long hours of the day. And that is an uh
that is a choice that I can make because
I have the economic means to make that
choice. I think the as we progress
further I think people will care a lot
more about like who is on the other side
of the experience that they're getting
and I think um that that which is um
rare will get more valuable
>> and and so even if like stable coins
come about and billions of agents come
about like being able to uh be in
relationship with another human is now
going to like disappear and like that's
probably going to get more valuable and
hopefully if all these agents are doing
all this work for us. I am hopefully in
relationship with as many humans as I
want to be in relation and it's deep and
meaningful and all of that.
>> But then the flip side of this as well
is shouldn't be people be building for
agents and not humans if agents are
going to be the bigger part of the
economy. That's what we're building like
we're building our developer platform
for the next 12 months we believe is
still going to be like developer first
but like next year sometime it flips
where uh agents are the developers and
and they sort of come in and they are
like because it's already the case if
you ask your coding agent like what
should I use like the coding agent
typically has gone from like
recommending three things to one thing
and next year there will be an evolution
of this where the coding you don't ask
the agent what you want to use you're
just telling them like please please
build it and
>> so when that happens like the agent is
like showing up for your developer
platform. So that means everyone in the
audience who's building should make sure
that just like you had accessible
websites, you have agent accessible
websites, right?
>> Y and you want to create like you know
we want to create like uh data on the
internet uh now
so that like when the agents come like
in like 9 months 12 months time they can
look at like history of uh like the
opportunity is right now basically.
>> So so an early indication that we're
headed quickly in this direction is
programmatic advertising.
>> Yes. which is which I think count
account accounts for well the percent of
online
uh advertising is roughly 25 30% already
programmatic and that happened really
quickly so I think that is showing us
the way that's why I come back to the
infrastructure question which um
>> you might
>> yeah I think you know this is incredibly
exciting and a bit scary uh you know
like we always going to have this thing
I think do Kathy Like you've seen all of
this before almost anyone else, right?
And you've gone through periods of
dismissal, fear, and optimism from the
investor community.
>> Yeah.
>> Where are we now in all of that? And how
do you see it evolving? Because all of
the science fiction is becoming science
fact.
>> I know,
>> as Alex likes to say, we're speed
running every science fiction trope all
at the same time.
>> Yes. It's been fascinating to to be ARC
in at this time because um I founded ARC
for this time because because this techn
of this technology revolution um but
because of the tech and telecom bust in
the early 2000s and then even more so
after 0809
the the institutional world the in in
public equities uh shifted either to
passive so just mimicking indexes. Uh
and of course the future uh companies
that that are making this new world
happen are not big parts of the indexes
with the exception of a few maybe Muse
and Facebook and all of that Meta. Uh I
think the pendulum is going to start
swinging in the other direction. uh our
biggest uh proof point potentially that
we've reached a a a moment of change
here is what's happening this year in
the what we call the multiomics
revolution uh the life sciences space
that space was left for dead
>> I in the markets even though we were
getting more and more proof points that
this that a the most profound applic
application of AI is in health care.
Well, finally this year um anthropic and
open AI are talking about the health
care verticals and how this much I mean
each one of us is a data factory right
we have 35 to 40 trillion that's my
trillion 40 35 to 40 trillion cells in
our body six billion base pairs uh I
mean three billion base pairs of DNA and
uh you know we are walking proprietary
data factories and uh I do think that uh
that market waking up to that and
actually starting to pay some attention
is is giving me hope that the chat GPT
moment got us a little bit there but you
know you could still own the mag six and
be okay with that. Uh but you know the
companies that are really harnessing AI
in the health care space uh are not big
parts of the benchmark. So I do think
we're going to see more truly active
equity management. What do you think
when you saw Madna gain more than any
other stock has ever gained in a major
index in one day? Like what was your
reaction to that?
>> It makes sense. I mean these if if what
they've done and and what what seems to
be uh approved is uh is what we think it
is a vaccine against cancer that's
unbelievable. Um unbelievably good. Uh
so yeah I think these company I think
the health care space um is the most
undervalued underappreciated space in
terms of this theme. Uh but there are
going to be major winners and losers.
You really because health care, you
know, health care and tech, this is the
problem generally for health care and
tech uh do not play well when I in terms
of research meaning health care analysts
uh are are a little cautious when it
comes to tech and in fact very cautious
because moving fast and breaking things
does not work in healthcare right and
tech analysts don't like health care
because it's too bureaucratic, too
regulated, too political, too hostage to
insurance companies and reimbursement
cycles. And so, but but we probably have
the most massive convergence and and as
I said, the most profound application of
AI in health care and I think the light
bulb has just gone on this year.
>> Yeah. And Peter, you discussed how
longevity is finally tractable, right?
>> Yeah. uh you know I when I you know I'm
in front of audiences speaking about
longevity. I do that a lot to you know
wealthy family offices and YPO chapters
and so forth and I ask them honestly how
much of your wealth would you give for
an extra 20 or 30 healthy years or
reverse your age by 20 or 30 years. When
when they're honest about it it's nearly
everything. Uh it's the you know I think
of it's why I split my life between AI
and [clears throat] and longevity. I
think they're the two biggest markets
and two most impactful markets on the
planet.
Um Nquille uh one of the things we've
talked about on the podcast probably
about two months ago was President
Millle and his announcement.
Anybody from Argentina here in the room?
Okay. Uh so President Mille comes out
and says we're going to change the laws.
uh we want to attract all the AI
companies here. We're going to give
agents personhood.
>> Fascinating, right? So I think one of
the most interesting things is going to
be nation states providing a sort of uh
uh you know regulatory arbitrage to
attract companies in uh and and efforts
to them. What happens when AI agents
have personhood? Do you have you thought
about that?
I mean right now we haven't like I think
like what we have thought about is uh AI
agents acting on behalf of uh people but
uh it's sort of a middle ground like
does a is a it's sort of like a
corporation if an corporation was just
AI incorporated AI uh AI managed but had
a board of directors that was human and
then like the progression for that from
there is like what if the board of
directors were other AI actors as well
like what happens then that is not too
hard to imagine like essentially how
should like how should a company go
about getting incorporated and what kind
of economic output it's going to create
and and and who holds the liability for
the mistakes it makes and how does it
distribute its profit. So again that is
very imminent.
Board of directors of such a company or
ownership of such company is still with
um humans at least in my current
thinking. But not very hard to speculate
that an AI can go and use crypto rails
to form capital and uh and create and
find shareholders who are like willing
to give them capital so they can go and
act uh in the world. um probably this
decade. Uh but hard to speculate on like
what problems they will be focused on.
Maybe like medicine problems, maybe
something else. Yeah.
>> And this this sorry this would segue I
mean um this would uh combine with uh
the concept of uh distributed autonomous
organizations Dows as well. So very
crypto. Yeah. Dow has perfected this
idea of governance [snorts] uh amongst a
bunch of people who didn't know each
other and they were global and agents
are similar in that they are uh they are
global uh they don't know each other uh
and so Dows did construct like and this
happened in about four or five years ago
before they went out of fashion
>> uh but there is a lot of prior art uh
for the agents to train on on what
worked what didn't work there's a whole
notion quadratic funding uh that got
played with. So crypto has a lot of
these primitives available
for untrusted parties to coordinate and
and agents are fundamentally like new
novel entities that exist and once they
have personhood it's even more amazing
you can go figure out like what their
provenence is who gave them why did they
get the why did they get the personhood
but yeah so I I agree like I think there
will be new models of funding and they
won't look like the models of funding
like going to a bank and like raising
There will probably be uh internet
native uh models of funding. I would not
be surprised if one of these agents
creates their own token and has their
own version of proof of work and and has
like a very complex economy built inside
of it and using tokens to coordinate
that.
>> Yeah, I think you can say that Dows kind
of lacked intelligence like they went
>> well they were human intelligence
[laughter]
>> but it was like direct. I think the
advent of AI now to create decentralized
intelligent organizations is
fascinating.
>> But I had a query about that. If you
have digital organizations, digital
entities, isn't that just the metaverse?
Like you've come from meta [laughter]
>> to circle, you know, where you did the
AR glasses and more. Like is actually
what we describe as the metaverse not as
this place that you play games, but a
whole digital economy of humans and
entities. Is that not actually coming
true actually finally now? Plus you can
make it look cool with the meta glasses
and other things.
>> Yeah, for me personally like so I did
work on the AR glasses uh at Meta uh by
>> Are you happy with the results?
>> I'm happy with the results. Yes, I think
the Rayban glasses were uh a good first
step. Uh the Orion glasses were a good
proof point and now I'm not there. I'm
sure they're working on new things. Um
and so for me always the met was less
about the 3D. I think the 3D is
exciting. Being able to wear your
glasses and walk around uh uh uh like
essentially CGI is exciting, but what is
more exciting is that there's just a
layers and layers and layers of
intelligence in the world uh that is
just waiting to be discovered, right?
Like Pokémon Go was a great example.
Like it is a metaverse because like you
don't know how many uh Pokemon are there
at any given stop like you know and like
you see people like tapping into these
layers of intelligence walking the world
trying to like capture uh Pokemon. And I
thought it was just f I would never do
it but like I thought it was just
fascinating as an example of like where
people find meaning and like how it sort
of that meaning sits in the physical
world alongside us, right? Like which is
which is what the met should be. It
doesn't need to be 3D. And so will these
AI entities present meaning? Absolutely.
They already have. I think they passed
the Turing test three years ago. Um so I
think they will present meaning. They
will present connection and so you will
have these like new weird societies
emerge which will be hybrid between
humans and AIs where there will be
meaning created which is metaverse in my
opinion. Yeah.
>> You might continue.
>> Yes. I think take that to Kathy. You
know like we have media, we have
generative media all coming through. we
have this new layer being attached like
what do you see is super exciting in
that space because you've got kind of
the physicality of you know Teslas and
things like that you have the financial
rails but it seems like there's a whole
world that could come from entertainment
from education from engagement like
what's really exciting you around that
the potential there
>> well as you're saying that um I think
and the other thing we talk a lot about
is space too right but there is another
digital I mean another world that is
happening and it's happening and it's
going to it's going to move in you know
move at a much faster pace. Um we now
have immutable property rights in the
digital world.
>> Yes. And so I think and and you know the
best way to lift people and countries
and ecosystems out of poverty or
inactivity is property rights. So
>> Amen.
>> I I I think you know I'm excited about
the space generally. You probably know a
lot more about and have a much better
idea about what's going to happen. Um
but we have um set up our research team
so that we have an enterprise AI analyst
team and a consumer AI analyst team and
we're spending a lot of time you know
talking about okay this new device is
has mused the muse charm is that going
to amount to anything um uh [laughter]
and and reflect on okay the handset
would we really So, could the handset
just become an, you know, a focus of
entertainment really after all and this
other gadget, you know, moves into our
work lives in some way? I don't know.
So, we're we're debating a lot of things
right now.
>> Nquille, um, you're building a financial
infrastructure
for an economy that doesn't yet exist.
[clears throat]
>> It exists, but it's not
>> it's nent. Yeah,
>> it's just beginning.
>> Yeah.
>> What are the hardest problems you still
have to solve
>> to get to the vision you have in 5 or 10
years? And then why did you build your
own blockchain?
>> Yeah. Uh
I think the two the two answers are
related. Uh let's start with something
as simple as me making a payment to you
on a blockchain. There is this concept
of payment finality. uh and when two
banks interact like they need to have
that method of interaction has to have
this property of payment finality. No
other blockchain today has this property
in the market. So if you believe you
want to get like existing banks,
existing institutions, existing
enterprises on this infrastructure, you
need to give them guarantees that are
not possible to give using existing
infrastructure. So um so one example is
payment finality. Another example is uh
in a lot of public uh blockchains run on
unknown validators. So unknown val
validation validating a transaction is
just looking at the block and making
sure it's not ill-formed and then
everybody achieves consensus on it and
says this is a good block. This is how
the transaction should be recorded. Now
for a lot of institutions around the
world not knowing who's doing the
validation is a big problem because they
worry about security. they worry about
like uh they worry about uh North Korea
being in the money flow like there's
just all kinds of things that they're
worried about. So we have a known
validator set like uh on our on our on
our blockchain. The next thing we
tackled was privacy because when you and
I transact it's not okay for the world
to know how much money we have in the
bank account in our bank accounts or for
that matter what this what is the value
of this transaction. So how do you solve
that problem at sufficient scale where
you can achieve the TPS that you were
talking about? Because a lot of privacy
solutions are very expensive. They're
computationally expensive.
>> So how do you solve it in a way that's a
systems way of solving it
>> but it preserves the sort of it fits
within existing regulatory frameworks
because you can't blow up the existing
regulatory frameworks just because you
have a good idea. So we saw privacy uh
as as being another example and then
then it's cost like we are um I was just
looking at some data today something
costs like uh uh 0.005 cents on ARC to
settle and cost 89 cents on uh uh on
Ethereum to settle. This is just some
data we got yesterday on our P50
transactions. So you can do the ratio on
like what the cost is. And so if you
have a lot of these agents executing a
lot of transactions and you have to
believe that in the future if these
markets are super efficient the way they
get efficient is they transact right
like they essentially move value back
and forth. There is price discovery. You
find the inefficiency and you sort of
like remove the inefficiency by moving
value around. So your settlement cost
has to be really really low and it has
to be significantly lower than what it
is today because you these are massive
public databases right and you're
competing with databases that you're
running internally like a MySQL database
or something like that but now you have
to make it uh scalable to the world and
auditable to the whole world. So cost
was another issue. So these are the
problems that we've been working on. I
think like in terms of what needs to
solve still. I do think uh for the
agentic stack uh we need uh we need to
make this transition into this world in
which these agents have personhood that
they are liable uh for making mistakes
uh that they have work history that I I
can rely on before I hire them. Uh there
are simple concepts like if for coding
agents today, if you're using them on
the open internet, if you're not paying
uh somebody $200 a month, uh you're
actually paying first and then the
you're waiting for the coding result to
come back. And so there are that could
be really problematic, right? Like so
there are all of these things that like
go into making to essentially reworking
every layer and every assumption of what
it means to be a financial
infrastructure.
>> All right. So the so the woolly mammoth
in the room to use uh Alex's joke
is when do banks disappear?
>> I don't think they disappear. Like I I
have I have no desire for
>> I know you don't
>> but I I hear the list of things that
that is going to be possible.
>> Yeah.
>> It feels like it's substantially a
significant amount of what banks do
today.
>> Yeah.
>> Do they do they know they're cooked?
My hope is the banks are going to work
with us and like make this transition. I
think every new technology change
presents like new challenges and new
opportunities. Some people will
transition with us and some won't. So I
don't know if they're cooked. Uh I think
that's a tough one. Yeah,
>> I understand you work with them.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> Yeah. So Kathy, like um last year Unitry
sold 11,000 robots, humanoids, right?
We've have the Optimus and other things
coming up. We have GDP growth forecasts
going through the roof. We make about 70
million cars, 70 million motorcycles a
year. When are we actually going to see
robots out in the world making a real
impact on GDP like humanoid robots?
>> What's your what's your timeline?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. So, uh, we according to our
research and our director of research,
Tasha Keiny, um, she's director of
research for autonomous technology and
robotics. She's here today.
>> Awesome.
>> Um, [clears throat]
>> will she be there tonight? So, CA
Kathy's doing a session this evening uh,
on her 2026 big ideas report, you know,
and come and dive in deep with her on
this. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um, I think Tasha has Oh, maybe
she's coming. I don't know. Okay. I know
you'll be there.
>> Um uh so we have from a a research point
of view concluded that um compared to a
robo taxi, a humanoid robot is 200,000
times more complex with obviously the
the hands being uh the the most
complicated part. Uh, so while Elon says
maybe late 28 into 29 scaling, we would
put that a couple of years later.
>> You mean he would be off on timing?
[laughter]
>> Yes, it's El Elon's time. So, um, but
yes, I mean, one of the I mean, because
it's such a a personal question in a in
a sense, everybody thinks, "Oh my gosh,
could I have a robot in my house?
who would do all my housework. Uh is
that possible? Will that happen? And and
the answer is yes. It's going to take
years, but uh um we we do think so. And
we think you know the reason Tesla is
further we believe furthest ahead on
this is it's the same three technology
platforms that are converging in
humanoid robots as it is in robo taxis.
So they are robots.
they uh they uh are effectively battery
operated electric and they're powered by
AI just like robo taxis. So he's you
know from a complexity point of view
we're we're very close to solving
completely the robo taxi pro uh problem.
I think if any of you uh are driving
with now your FSDs with the latest
software updates.
>> I love it. I don't touch the touch
wheel. We, you know, at home we have two
Teslas and it's like it's magic.
>> It truly is. I I would never drive
another car. That's not a commercial for
Tesla. It's like just I want my time
back and it's such a better driver than
I am. Just ask my wife. [laughter]
>> Well, you know, you know what? It is
true. You know,
>> statistically, yes. 10 times better.
>> Oh, well, I don't know about your
driving, but [laughter]
>> and I'm not even funny. I don't know
what that lies. I'm not I'm not at all.
Um, no, both Whimo and Tesla, I think
I'm not sure if Tesla has uh disclosed,
but we believe Whimo has disclosed that
it has surpassed human drivers in terms
of safety. Uh, and uh, we believe uh,
Tesla is there as well. I don't think
they've put out those stats yet. Uh, so
yes, and and they're going to be 10
times and a hundred times and a thousand
times safer. So yes.
>> Yeah. The Whimo stats, I did the
numbers. If all cars were as safe as
Whimos, there'd be 40,000 less deaths
per year and about 400 billion less in
medical fees.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, that's right. [applause] If
if we were That's right. There are 40
roughly 40,000 deaths in the US
>> and uh we could save those. I think
there are 1.25 25 to 1.5 million around
the world auto deaths per year.
>> You know, it's it's the the secondary
externalities are fascinating, right? Um
if that happens, the number of organ
donors goes down
>> significantly, right? Which is why the
other side of the business, the work of
Martin Rothblat and and George Church on
being able to generate, you know,
replacement organs is so extraordinary.
And what's fascinating is the counter
movement coming from the liability
lawyers
>> saying we've got far less business if
cars aren't crashing.
>> Yes.
>> 180 billion a year they get.
>> Amazing. Amazing. Um Kathy, you know, we
opened up the show today talking about
fear, the pandemic of fear that's going
on. uh and I think very unfortunately
and my mission and the mission of of our
podcast is to give people hope and
optimism try and counter that fear with
what I call datadriven optimism.
Absolutely. Right. Not just
>> empty like datadriven optimism.
>> How is that impacting the markets today?
that must have, you know, some current
or future. You know, we're seeing uh the
numbers are insane. Like 80% of
Americans fear AI. You know, 73% say no
data center in my backyard, which is
more than people say no nuclear reactor
in my backyard.
>> And the flip is true in China, uh where
it's 80% pro.
Uh what's how is this impacting you? I
love your investment thesis. I always
have. You're investing in the
singularity. Uh anyway, your your
thoughts.
>> So on the data center, it it is
fascinating. I agree with you. Um
because I think there's already proof
out there that putting a data center in
your state or your your city or whatever
um is actually over time going to lower
your electricity costs.
um nuclear power uh it stopped in its
tracks in the 70s because of regulation.
Now we're going full steam ahead and
sure it's going to take a while for this
to play out. But if we had not gone off
nuclear, if we had not regulated it, and
this is a lesson we need to tell policy
makers today. If we had not regulated,
electricity prices in the United States
would be uh 50% of what they are now.
>> It's a travesty.
>> It is. It is. So regulation is a menace
and it's up to us uh and and we're going
out there with this you know the the the
scares about AI generally and we're
going out there and uh all of us on our
team trying to bring data uh to you know
to to light for these politicians. I
even faced in Florida there's been a
political backlash and it's a business
businessfriendly state. Yeah. And but
you face the the policy maker with facts
and I noticed the advertising has
dropped a lot of that um that dynamic.
So I think we have to face we have to
face them you know approach them and say
do you understand and that's what we
give our research away and we hope it
gets into policy circles. Sometimes it
does sometimes it doesn't. Yeah, I did a
a podcast with Michael Katzios at the
White House, uh the head of office of
science, technology, policy, and I'm
like, Michael, who inside the government
is dealing with this misinformation and
trying to actually help Americans be
more confident and they didn't have an
answer and that worries me.
>> It feels a runaway in that regard.
>> We we have to tell the stories though. I
think like if we are constantly in the
news talking about AI taking away jobs,
I think we should expect this reaction.
AI has to make housing cheaper, it has
to make education better and it has to
make healthcare more accessible, not
just people living longer. And so like
if we can tell those stories, I do think
like we we have a real shot of like
turning the narrative around. But
nobody's telling those stories, right?
like those stories get anchored in like
well AI is going to come and like you
know you will have less office jobs and
okay great then what are my kids going
to do
>> I call it the crisis news network it's
my abbreviation for
>> CN yes
and what's so surprising is the numbers
are are not supporting that job loss
maybe at entry level as I mentioned
earlier today uh but I actually think
we're going to end up with labor
shortages and that's where we should go
out talking about. Yeah,
>> technology is a net job creator always.
Sure, there's short-term disappointment.
Yes, it's true. It's [applause] a net
job creator. It is. It is. And what you
have to say because people say, "Okay,
well, what are the jobs?" Well, in the
early 90s, did we know did we know
anything about influencers or Airbnb or
Uber? No, we didn't. We couldn't
conceptualize it, right? uh there are
many jobs we cannot conceptualize right
now. So I do an exercise go to chashbt
and or to gro and and say okay I want
you to consult with uh futurists,
scientists, engineers, science fiction,
uh economists, strategists and tell me
what the new jobs associated with and I
would put in our five major platforms.
What will they be? And you know the
reason I talk about new worlds like
space obviously it is a new world but
asteroid minor did come up in one of
those jobs and it was like gosh I
haven't even been using that
>> near and dear to my heart. Yes.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. So, and same
with the digital world, you know,
property rights, you know, you know,
we're what I what I love about this
country, you know, if you look at um I
saw the statistics, this statistic this
week, 90% of all the corporate bonds uh
to fund uh data centers all all 90% of
them are have are US and I go to the
rest of the world and they are, you know
that I don't see the animal spirits. I I
do see the fear there. So, the irony is
the headlines might be reading this, but
the animal spirits are are alive and
kicking and we're beginning to look, the
market's near all-time highs.
>> Crazy.
>> Yeah. Right. Even though interest rates
are going up and interest rates will go
up if growth really picks up
dramatically and they should go up.
That's the market working.
>> Yeah. I think this is the bull case for
America, right? USDC circulating faster.
The buildout that you've seen, we have
no securitization in Europe. We have no
energy. And surely this could kind of be
the bull case. You have the muses, the
instincts, the Grock bots of the world.
The base case is be more, do more.
You've always felt constrained by
creativity, by access, and this is
breaking down all those barriers. And in
fact, you look at bonds. Bonds are so
cumbersome. Like nickel, what do you see
about the future of securitization of
all assets? Because if you can
securitize a dollar, why can't you
securitize anything? Particularly with
the intelligence we have today.
>> Yeah, you should. Like I think uh XUS
that is more common. I think the US
securities laws are a little more
complicated. They need to evolve uh or
to allow for more experimentation and
like the SEC just is putting out new
rules as we speak, right? So um I do
think uh for one of the things that is
amazing about USDC is that is
essentially exports the dollar into the
world. Why is exporting the dollar into
the world good? It's because people do
real work. They make uh they take their
local currency and then they sell their
local currency and then they buy the
dollar. They're essentially lending us
their labor. They're lending us their
money, right? So that's why stable coins
are really important strategically for a
country because if you want to raise
debt, if you want to grow and you uh you
you have such high interest rates like
you want to lower those interest rates,
you want to go out and like collect
money from people so they can invest in
your growth and then you can pay pay
them back like and one way of doing that
is stable coins, right? So that is so
that is like a that is why why that's
why sort of I've been at circle for 5
years and for the first couple of years
I was so confused. I was like why don't
you want this uh America because uh you
can get [laughter] you can raise more
money.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah. You can raise a trillion dollars
from the world and and and people
willing to give you money because like
they believe in in the dollar like it's
it's so important. So from there I do
think there are other assets like I
think treasuries will get tokenized. I
do think bonds are already uh being
tokenized. When you tokenize, you do two
things like um both inside the US and
outside the US. You first you make it
possible to access 24/7 markets. Why is
accessing 24/7 markets valuable? Because
that means you're more capital
efficient. Like you you cannot trade a
treasury after 5:00 or 4:00 Eastern.
You'll know this better than me. Uh till
like Monday morning. And so
>> great, no more sleep anymore ever.
[laughter] Yeah, there already your your
agent will handle it for you. Um, and so
so treasure t so one is like the you're
essentially constantly managing capital
efficiency, capital allocation and
you'll be surprised at how much money
that is stuck. So in just one example
just in the international banking system
the money that is being sent sent
between uh countries at any given time
right now there's about $3 trillion that
is probably in motion that is not being
used to go back into the economy and
that is not being used to go back into
the economy for the simple reason that
the technology and the settlement
protocols are very old. So imagine a
world and if you believe uh the world is
a hundred trillion dollar economy I'm
making numbers numbers up if you had $3
trillion more afloat to invest in the
world economy what would that mean
that's a pretty significant thing
>> right and so that's why some of what we
do matters uh the other thing it'll open
up is security securitization will open
up is like access for people and it
works both ways people in the rest of
the world want to own Tesla uh circle
stock we went public last Here circle
stock has been tokenized by third
parties and it is one of the most traded
uh tokenized stocks in the world and
it's all XUS and people traded XUS
because they want to participate in
Circle but they have no good way of
doing it outside of owning a tokenized
version of uh of Circle and so all of
that should get normalized. Why why is
that good for America? It's good for
America because now people in like other
countries are investing in America.
They're saying like look, I believe
American companies are the best. I want
to give my money to this company versus
some other company. And it works the
other way around too. If these countries
are able to tokenize their securities if
they're able to modernize their
financial systems, more money will flow
in because you will you will not be
relying on the local regulator just
telling you something. your money is not
going to disappear because it's going to
be in a smart contract because you can
audit how the financial ecosystem works.
So if you want to raise money, if you
want to for these other countries that
don't have the AI infrastructure, they
want to raise money, they want to bring
capital in, then you have to give better
guarantees and better returns on the
capital. It cannot be the case that I
invest a bunch of money and then the
company I invested in gets nationalized
or the money I invested in gets devalued
significantly. Like all of that matters
to investors. So tokenization is just an
inevitability like I think it's just
going to pick up much like agents doing
more cognitive work is going to pick up
like you know taking that work
securitizing it lending it uh lending
against it borrowing borrowing against
it um all these are just all new
primitives that are coming. You guys
feel the speed of the economy
accelerating as we talk crazy.
>> Can I just add this is this is a really
important conversation. You know that
there has been a narrative out there
that you know US exceptionalism is dead
right and everyone was pointing out the
dollar going down last year. Um if
you'll notice the dollar is started to
go up and uh this happened in the 80s as
well when we had put in place very
businessfriendly policies. the dollar
doubled in in the early 80s with really
good policies. So I think because of
everything we've been talking about here
that the dollar is actually going to go
up. So it's going to be a win-win for
people who are using stable coins in the
rest of the world. And then I'd be
remiss certainly my team would feel I'd
be remiss. Uh we just securitied
securitized our our venture fund that
came that that was announced yesterday.
So
>> congratulations Kathy on that. I I want
to close us out on a topic that we've
discussed a few times on the abundance
stage. Um and Kathy, thank you. You're
coming back to Abundance 360 in March.
We're going to have Brett Adcock there.
We're the CEO of Helion. We're going to
have Feay Lee. It's going to be an
amazing amazing event in in March. Um
when you are on stage, uh you were
bullish about hitting a million dollars
per Bitcoin. Uh I am curious if you're
still bullish about that. And then any
concerns about the energy sucking sound
of of AI over Bitcoin mining?
>> Well, I do think that Bitcoin Well,
there were three things that hit it. The
flash crash, uh quantum computing fears,
uh which we think are uh way overblown,
and AI taking all the oxygen out of the
room and and taking miners away, right?
Um, so we we have there's there's been
one change. It's stable coins. Stable
coins are usurping a role that 10 years
ago we thought Bitcoin was going to
play. But it makes sense. This, you
know, these people live hand-to-mouth.
And this makes a lot of sense. Uh, but
it hasn't lost the three major roles.
It's a, you know, it's a tech, it
introduced a technology, a native a
currency native to to the internet. So,
wasn't there before. Uh, it's a global
monetary system, private rules-based,
that's critical. Uh, and it's, uh, it's
the first of its kind, or it was the
first of its kind in a new asset class.
Very low correlation even between gold
and Bitcoin. That correlation since 2019
has been 0.1. So, hardly correlated at
all. And now, Bitcoin is going up
relative to gold. I believe that Worsh
is going to be very good for um for
Bitcoin from this point of view. I think
the gold price is going to go down and
uh and and yet uh and and that that will
to the extent people were playing that
they'll be looking for the other um uh
>> safe harbor
>> safe harbor store of value. uh and uh so
we do we have not changed our forecast
uh those revolutions haven't been
changed and the more stable coins uh
kind of grease the skids uh and you know
get more people talking about once
you've once you've got your stable coin
income and you're trying to figure out
okay I'm I'm actually making money now
where do I put it I think Bitcoin's
going to get a bit from the emerging
markets as well as we always thought it
would
>> all right we're going Wrap it there.
Ladies and gentlemen, please give it up
for Kathy Wood, [applause]
Niel Shandock, and Immod
[music]